[
    {
        "question": "An item of appropriation in partnership profit and loss account is",
        "optionA": "employees' salaries",
        "optionB": "interest on partners' loan",
        "optionC": "interest on partners' capital",
        "optionD": "partners' drawings",
        "answer": "interest on partners' capital"
    },

    {
        "question": "A business is required at par when the",
        "optionA": "purchase consideration is greater than the net value",
        "optionB": "net assets is greater than the liabilitties",
        "optionC": "purchase consideration equals net value",
        "optionD": "purchase consideration equals goodwill",
        "answer": "purchase consideration equals net value"
    },

    {
        "question": "Recurrent expenditure are expenses for the period not exceeding",
        "optionA": " 10 years",
        "optionB": "2 years",
        "optionC": "5 years",
        "optionD": "1 year",
        "answer": "1 year"
    },

    {
        "question": "Cost accounting entails the provision of information",
        "optionA": "for descision making",
        "optionB": "for investment purposes",
        "optionC": "to stockholders",
        "optionD": "to shareholders",
        "answer": "for descision making"
    },

    {
        "question": "The channel through which all government borrowing and domestic lending transactions pass is called",
        "optionA": "agency fund",
        "optionB": "national loan fund",
        "optionC": "special trust fund",
        "optionD": "contingency fund",
        "answer": "contingency fund"
    },

    {
        "question": "What does the two supporting horses in the nigeria coat of arm representThe body constitutionally charged with the responsibility of examining the audited accounts of the Federation and other reports as referred by the National Assembly is the",
        "optionA": "External Audit Committee",
        "optionB": "Public Accounts Committee",
        "optionC": "Internal Audit Committee",
        "optionD": "Public Audit Committee",
        "answer": "Public Accounts Committee"
    },

    {
        "question": "The most appropriate basis for apportioning inventory holding cost among departments is to use the value of",
        "optionA": "closing stock",
        "optionB": "average stock",
        "optionC": "opening stock",
        "optionD": "purchases",
        "answer": "opening stock"
    },

    {
        "question": "The accumulation fund of a non-trading concern can equally be referred to as",
        "optionA": "members' equity",
        "optionB": "general fund",
        "optionC": "share capital",
        "optionD": "surplus fund",
        "answer": "members' equity"
    },

    {
        "question": "The Partnership Deed normally specifies?",
        "optionA": "how profit or losses are to be shared",
        "optionB": "the capital to be contributed annually",
        "optionC": "the profit that should be earned annually",
        "optionD": "how salaries are paid to employees",
        "answer": "how profit or losses are to be shared"
    },

    {
        "question": "An outright sale of a partnership amounts to the",
        "optionA": "change of sharing ratio of vendors",
        "optionB": "purchase of rights of a dead partner",
        "optionC": "admission of a new partner",
        "optionD": "compensation of vendors by the purchase",
        "answer": "change of sharing ratio of vendors"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following items does not feature in the balance sheet of a club? ",
        "optionA": "Arrears of current year's subscription",
        "optionB": "Salary arrears paid in the current year",
        "optionC": "Advances subscription in respect of a coming year",
        "optionD": "Rental income received in advance",
        "answer": "Salary arrears paid in the current year"
    },

    {
        "question": "One of the advantages of the shortcomings of single entry procedures is that ",
        "optionA": "a trial balance is not available",
        "optionB": "profits are overestimated",
        "optionC": "there are no subsidiary books",
        "optionD": "there are no control accounts",
        "answer": "a trial balance is not available"
    },

    {
        "question": "A general journal contains",
        "optionA": "date, narration, folio, debit, and purchases",
        "optionB": "date, narration, folio, debit and purchase",
        "optionC": "folio, credit, date, debit and sales",
        "optionD": "debit, credit, narration, date and discount",
        "answer": "date, narration, folio, debit, and purchases"
    },

    {
        "question": "In a manufacturing company, the total cost of goods produced is equivalent to",
        "optionA": "purchases",
        "optionB": "sales",
        "optionC": "cost of goods sold",
        "optionD": "cost of materials used",
        "answer": "purchases"
    },

    {
        "question": "A fixed cost is fixed only in relation to",
        "optionA": "a given period of time and a range of activities",
        "optionB": "a given period of time and the nature of activity",
        "optionC": "the quantity of goods sold",
        "optionD": "the quality of goods produced",
        "answer": "a given period of time and the nature of activity"
    }
]